{
    "quizzes": [
      {
        "title": "week4",
        "questions": [
          {
            "index": 1,
            "question": "Which of these is a deterministic factor?",
            "options": ["environmental variation", "forest fire", "death rate", "diseases"],
            "correct": "death rate"
          },
          {
            "index": 2,
            "question": "I tried growing vegetables under my teak plantation, but the vegetable plants died out. I should be concerned about",
            "options": ["autophagy", "allelophagy", "autopathy", "allelopathy"],
            "correct": "allelopathy"
          },
          {
            "index": 3,
            "question": "The movement of lions across the Gir landscape is an example of",
            "options": ["diffusion", "secular dispersal", "jump dispersal", "drifting"],
            "correct": "diffusion"
          },
          {
            "index": 4,
            "question": "The geographical distribution of a species will be controlled by that environmental factor for which the organism has the narrowest range of tolerance. This is the statement for",
            "options": ["Liebig’s law of the minimum", "Liebig’s law of the maximum", "Shelford’s law of tolerance", "Shelford’s law of intolerance"],
            "correct": "Shelford’s law of tolerance"
          },
          {
            "index": 5,
            "question": "The regular, seasonal movement of animals, often along fixed routes is called",
            "options": ["translocation", "migration", "dispersal", "drifting"],
            "correct": "migration"
          },
          {
            "index": 6,
            "question": "Which of these is a stochastic factor?",
            "options": ["birth rate", "death rate", "population structure", "environmental fluctuation"],
            "correct": "environmental fluctuation"
          },
          {
            "index": 7,
            "question": "The movement of individuals away from their place of birth or hatching or seed production into a new habitat or area to survive and reproduce is called",
            "options": ["translocation", "migration", "dispersal", "drifting"],
            "correct": "dispersal"
          },
          {
            "index": 8,
            "question": "Scarcity of food is a",
            "options": ["chemical factor", "demographic factor", "push factor", "pull factor"],
            "correct": "push factor"
          },
          {
            "index": 9,
            "question": "Which of these correctly represents the process of habitat fragmentation and loss?",
            "options": [
              "Original forest → Dissection → Perforation → Fragmentation → Attrition",
              "Original forest → Dissection → Attrition → Fragmentation → Perforation",
              "Original forest → Dissection → Perforation → Attrition → Fragmentation",
              "Original forest → Dissection → Fragmentation → Perforation → Attrition"
            ],
            "correct": "Original forest → Dissection → Perforation → Fragmentation → Attrition"
          },
          {
            "index": 10,
            "question": "A root zone treatment plant is an example of",
            "options": ["phytoremediation", "biological control", "biomagnification", "bioaccumulation"],
            "correct": "phytoremediation"
          }
        ]
      }
    ]
  }